Daniel Tang

Business Data Analyst
Portfolio: https://dtang29.github.io/

San Francisco, CA
T: +1.415.539.5369
E: dtang1529@gmail.com

Summary

Business Data Analyst with 3+ years experience working in a fast-paced tech environment; Excels at conducting analyses, implementing process improvements and reporting analytical results in an easily digestible visualization to help drive data-driven business decisions. Enjoys the process of learning new tools and up to date technologies to add value to my workflow in order to serve my team better.

Experience

Business Analyst, Google Payments, Business Operations (Vaco) - Mountain View 2018-02 to Present

- Maintained, created dashboards; monitored pipeline that fed data into high traffic usage dashboards
- Addressed priority bugs within our bug queue workflow (buganizer); Pulled ad-hoc analyses for product managers, analysts, specialists, etc utilizing SQL based language (GoogleSQL)
- Supported the design and implementation of overall dashboard design principles
- Performed QA tests to validate accuracy of data metrics during a transition of our primary transactions table in Q2 to include new relevant fields with better naming conventions
- Assisted on a project to improve the machine learning algorithm to identify users with good payment history, leading to a 3% improvement
- Created mapping for our existing decline reason codes to a more human readable naming convention and successfully applied it to all our primary tables and dashboards

Business Analyst, Youtube, Trust & Safety (Vaco) - San Bruno

2017-04 to 2018-02

- Supported Operation Managers with metrics gathering and slide creations for their business reviews that was presented to Youtube stakeholders
- Met with Vaco Leads and Managers weekly to gather requirements around changes in priority of the product/workflows
- Developed new Vaco onboarding/tracking process and manager tools which successfully increased managers' bandwidth

Business Data Analyst, Google Express, Transportation (SMX) - San Jose

2016-06 to 2017-03

- Performed ad hoc data analyses, develop and maintain new dashboards/reports
- Developed a quality dashboard to monitor missing parcel trend per driver per market, effectively reduced missing parcels by 70% in 4 weeks and reduced returns/replacements per order by~ 64% across several markets
- Conducted an analysis to pinpoint drivers who completed multiple stops with same delivery timestamps, sent out weekly reports to vendors with weekly trend and successfully reduced number of incidents by~ 80% in 5 weeks

Vendor Performance Manager, Google Express, Transportation (SMX) - San Jose 2015-12 to 2016-06

- Worked closely with fulfillment, forecasting & analytics team to monitor capacity and scheduling in adherence to forecast
- Maintained relationship with vendors with weekly calls to ensure overall quality and performance is addressed
- Developed and improved systems and tools to monitor staffing adherence and invoice auditing; Implemented courier scorecard to monitor overall performance and quality

Education

University of California, Berkeley Extension

Certificate, Data Analysis & Visualization, 2018-02 to 2018-08

Part time Data Analysis & Visualization Bootcamp by UC Berkeley Extension Program

University of California, Davis

Bachelor of Science in Managerial Economics/Business, Graduated Fall 2015

Additional Skills

Languages → SQL, Python, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Google Apps Script

Data Visualization → Google PLX dashboard, Google Data Studio, Tableau, D3, Leaflet, Plotly, Matplotlib

Data Mining/Wrangling → API Interactions, Web Scraping (Beautiful Soup, Selenium)

Databases → MongoDB, MySQL, Sqlite

Version Control → Github